Okay, I think it's time
to get
started. Um, so welcome to this
third monthly AMG go for GitHub office
hours call.
Um, and I can see we are 33 people right
now attending. So that's good. If more
attends, they are welcome.
Um, as we've done a few times before,
um, I'll go through like very shortly a
few slides about what's new and then
we'll open up for
questions in the Q&A pane in the
meeting. Please use the Q&A pane for
questions and not the chat.
Um, I'm right now sitting in the US and
in Lumpy we have
uh I think Alexander, Maria, and
Sebastian. So, we should be able to
answer all of your questions
together. Well, let's get started with
what's new. Um, yeah, by the way, we
also just recorded the launch event
video, so in a few days you will be able
to see what's new in in the next version
of Algo version 7. Um, right now we we
just launched
um version
6.4 a week ago. Um, and what's new in
that one is really a lot of the stuff
that we talked about in the last office
hours call. So, if you haven't like seen
the brief presentation of what's new
with GitHub app authentication and bet
secrets, incremental builds and stuff
like that, uh those are included in the
video of Algo office hours uh 2 like the
February edition. In this I'm going to
talk about the last two uh additions to
version 6.4 for the update Elgo system
files on multiple branches and the N get
feed select
mode also
[Music]
um in preview as of today maybe later
today maybe right now so it's right out
of the press uh the ability to to to set
BC container settings uh from settings
variables and publish to environment
from a pull request. So those things are
in preview right now and will also be
included in version seven of Elgo for
GitHub.
Um so
let's as as usual there's a repository
called Elgo office hours
2025-3 which contains the demos of the
features that I'm going to talk about
here. The update go system files on
multiple branches is really the ability
to run as it says update go system files
on multiple branches.
Um the algo for GitHub normally you'd
run the updated go system files but that
would then run on the branch that you're
running it on.
Now um now there's an additional field
where you can set the branches that you
want to include uh and then it will
update Elgo system files on all branches
to the template URL that you're
specifying. You can also run it on a
schedule which is highly recommended. So
you can you can set up this workflow
schedule and say include branches when
it is on the go system files and it will
run then um it will update all these
active branches that you have uh to the
latest version
um and keep you up to
date. There's a new setting called n get
feed select mode uh before version 6.4
four. This was hardcoded to latest
matching um and we had some partners
running into uh an issue where they
weren't wanted to change that to
earliest matching in some of their
builds. So now we created the setting
that you are able to u set to possible
values earliest matching earliest exact
latest or latest matching. The
difference between earliest and earliest
matching is that the earliest matching
is also taking dependencies into
consideration. So if you have
um I if if if you have an a dependency
and and you you're running on a specific
version of Business Central, it will
find the
earliest version of your dependency that
also matches the version of Business
Central that you're running on.
So um yeah enough for that PC container
helper settings earlier that was only
read from the repository settings file
the github algo settings JSON now it is
also run read from the settings
variables both orc settings and repo
settings. So stuff like memory limit can
be set globally if you want to set that
to like 16 GB or whatever. Also other
global settings that you have for BC
container helper uh can be set now in
these settings
variables. And the last one um publish
apps from a pull request which has been
uh requested by a few partners as well.
Like if you have like a pull request
open doing code reviews, you might want
to to to try to deploy the the artifacts
from that pull request to an environment
and actually do some manual testing as
well as code reviewing before you
approve the the pull request. And you
can do that now by specifying uh PR
underscore and then a pull request
number uh in your publish to
environment. And doing that will allow
you to uh publish the artifacts from
that pull request
to an environment.
Um the default setting for pull request
artifact uh retention is one day. So if
you wait a day or two before from from a
build
until until a pull request uh is is
deployed, you'll have to rerun the the
build from the pull request else the
artifact uh the artifacts from that pull
request will be uh
um expired. So you you you need some new
ones there.
Um yeah, with that I will change to open
discussion
and allow for questions
um and see
what what people have. Please use the
Q&A
pane. Let's see
here.
[Music]
Um, any
questions? Absolutely,
man. I hope people can hear
me as I've just been talking to
Okay. Is there plan to publish from PR
to docker containers or only for
sandboxes? Um, so it isn't anything we
are going
to invest in.
um because the we also don't have
publish
to publish to a docker container from
from normal artifacts. You can download
the artifacts and then you can
um and then you can yeah publish them to
a container yourself. Uh I'll I'll move
this one to
uh to the screen here.
Um yeah, so you can publish the
artifacts by downloading them. Uh and
and when you have a pull request built,
you will be able to see what the last
known good built is. So a pull request
will only if you have multiple projects
will only build and include the projects
in the PR artifacts uh that you actually
modified. So if you have multiple
projects, you might need to find the
missing artifacts from the last known
good build. There'll be a link to that
on the PR. So you'll be able to see last
no good build. Click that and find the
remaining artifacts there and then just
publish those to a container using
whatever
uh mechanisms you have. If you have an
online container somewhere
um Oliver Schulz
asks is this
uh we have the dependency probing paths
to pull apps in an exact version across
repository boundaries. Would it also be
possible via the Nougat packages in the
future?
Uh
yes, I mean it is possible now.
Um the the
the recommended so it depends on if it
is your own like internal
um if it's your internal dependencies or
it's your external dependencies.
internal dependencies. The recommended
uh dependency resolution mechanism is is
uh GitHub packages which you can set up
just by creating the GitHub packages
context secret. Then
um you will automatically have internal
uh dependency resolution using using
Nougat packages on on GitHub.
Um and that should work right now. If
you have like external dependencies to
third party then you have to set up
trusted nougat feeds but that should
also work uh either using exact versions
or I mean we don't recommend setting up
exact versions we recommend like using
the same the same versioning
uh select mechanism that business
central uses uh online as well which is
the default
Um is asking I'm learning this algo for
GitHub. Is it possible to get this in
Azure DevOps as well or any plans in the
future? And that is an absolute no. We
do not have resources to to create algo
for GitHub to or ago for Azure DevOps.
Um so algo go for GitHub is for GitHub
only. Morton asks uh when we write PTE
we often extend third party extensions
from app
source. I understand that we cannot we
can not download symbols but as I
understand we still limited when we want
to build and test our
PTE. You mean we can download symbols or
what? Uh I
guess I guess more than you need you you
mean that we so today we have a nougat
feed where we publish symbols from for
lapsource apps and this is automatically
included in the new in the dependency
search when you're
running and for that you can then
um you can build all apps but you
cannot test your uh PTE on a docker
container. If you only have the symbols
obviously then you need an online
environment and publish your app to an
online environment for with these uh
apps source dependencies.
What we hope is that more and more
partners will start
um publishing their appsource apps as
runtime packages and sharing those with
partners so that you'll be able to find
the runtime packages instead of the auto
generated symbols. Uh and then trusting
the partners nougat feed to to to do
that. uh and we know that we are missing
a few features uh for that and and that
is on our schedule to finalize the new
get uh features in in the upcoming
release meaning over the next half
year. Uh Ray is asking I would like to
build only one app from a repository
with two or more apps. Is that possible?
currently builds and deploys all my apps
in the
repo. Um,
so I'm expecting that uh this is the
feature that we we just released in
version 6.4 which is incremental builds.
So um if you see the video in the launch
event or the video from the last office
hours call, you'll see that you can now
set up incremental builds on on push. Um
meaning that whenever you you push some
modifications to the repo, it will only
build the apps that you actually
modified in that uh
push. meaning and then it will also then
only deploy that app uh to your
environment when it deploys. It'll it'll
find the last known good built and and
try to deploy the app from that and if
you already have that deployed then
it'll skip that. Um so it sounds like
you are talking about the feature we
just released there.
Right.
Um Christian is asking is there a simple
guide on how we can switch from Azure
DevOps to GitHub uh to use uh algo
GitHub? Is there an overview of which
functions are
available out of the box? Uh how can
existing DevOps pipelines be easily
transferred to GitHub
actions? Um so if you are moving from
Azure DevOps to ALGO for GitHub the
suggestion is to use the uh actions
already available or the pipelines and
workflows already available in Elgo for
GitHub and uh just discard the ones that
you have in Azure DevOps. Um
uh what you can do is you can yeah get
started on using
ak.ms/algo workshop. That one will take
you through like a lot of the different
things that are on an algo. Um it is a
learning curve and you need to like yeah
get used to a number of different things
how things work where they'll go.
probably you'll find that the majority
of things that you're already doing is
is somehow available in in algo for
GitHub as well. Um and you shouldn't
need to actually build any pipelines or
transform any pipelines or anything like
that. You can just use the ones that are
there. There's a lot of settings that
like dictates the mechanism on how Go
works.
Um and and and those can be found on
aka.ms/go settings. Uh that's like a
reference of all the settings that are
available. But but yeah, probably
uh the workshop is a good starting point
and also the scenarios on
github/microsoft-go where there's a
number of scenario documentations as
well. We know that we still need to
generate more documentation and I have
promised to get started on
that. So Oliver should ask, "Hey me
again, it's about dependencies for our
own partner apps in the customer
repository. It pulls the direct
dependencies correctly, but it searches
for the indirect dependencies for a very
long time and often aborts. It would
probably be more correct to say that we
need a method to obtain each app
individually
via GitHub
Nugget.
Um, I would like suggest that you create
an issue with this and let's look at why
it doesn't behave like it should.
um indirect dependencies. I'm not sure
what we're talking about there. is that
runtime packages
or yeah I suggest you create an an issue
on on um GitHub Microsoft ago and let's
uh figure out
um where
yeah so last says in the last office
hours you shared a link to a GitHub repo
where you had the feature you shown set
up I cannot access the video. Could you
share the link to the repo
again? Yes.
So the link to the repo in this in this
one
is github.com business
centralapps-go-off
hours-2025-3 for March um and two for
February. So it's a two instead of a
three in this URL. I'll take that. Oh, I
couldn't do
that. I maybe get the link
and take this and paste that
into the chat.
So the three is for this monster, the
two is for the other
one.
Um, so there's a chat here. Tom says
that I spend a lot of time trying to get
my DevOps pipeline converted to run in
GitHub without succeeding. Today I'm
happily using the workflows within ALGO.
So I suggest to other using workflow
delivered with
Algo. Thanks for that
Tom. Back to the
Q&A. Alexander is asking, "What is the
status of automatically uninstalling old
apps when ALG go deploys to an
environment?" Uh, the status of that is
that um it was added
to the uninstalled capability was added
to Business Central a month ago or
something like that. So it should be
deployed now. So it's something that we
can we now can implement in algo. We we
couldn't do that before because the
ability to uninstall or unpublish
actually an an old app um was not
available. That is available now. So, we
should look into getting that uh
added to the publish to environment so
that it it automatically unpublishes the
old app instead of leaving it there and
and and like
um ends up having like a lot of of
different versions of the same app
published
there.
Other questions?
So Alexander is asking is it currently
possible or are there any plans in the
future to allow multiple organizational
variables? We have different settings
for our internal and our PTE apps.
Well, it's it's currently not possible.
I have thought about adding like a
setting
to allow you to point to a different
variable and you could have that in a
conditional setting. So, you could kind
of um do it like that. You could also
create an organizational variable that
have conditional settings for a lot of
stuff.
[Music]
Um maybe if we can understand the the
exact scenario, we can make sure that we
uh that we take that into consideration
if we are to to modify any behavior
there.
Um so maybe describe that discussions or
issues on a
go. There's a question
from Cataline Maria Alexander. Do you
want to take that?
Yeah, sure. Um, so there's really
there's no direct integration between
it'll go for GitHub and Azure DevOps,
but GitHub does come with some uh apps
that you can install on your repository.
Like there's the Azure boards
integration let you kind of link a pull
request or an GitHub issue to a work
item in Azure DevOps. Uh we're using
that within Microsoft and it's I think
it's working just fine. Uh so you you
can just add like AB hashtag and then
the work item ID in your in the
description and then it it creates a
link and you can click on that and you
can kind of seamlessly go between Azure
DevOps and
GitHub. Uh but it probably won't be as
well integrated as you know you're used
to if you're 100% within Ashure DevOps.
Um but there are some integrations that
you can take advantage of.
Thanks.
So Alexander is asking is there already
possibility? Are there any plans to add
check to determine if there were any
code changes before CI/CD decides to
deploy the
app? Um, so the way incremental builds
work is that it will only build the apps
that has changes since the last known
good build.
[Music]
Um, and that means that um when you have
a an incremental build, then it will
actually copy the artifacts from the
last known good build. meaning that if
you if you open up your your apps uh
artifact from build, you might find
version
uh like two apps from this build and
three apps from the previous build.
Um, and when it then comes to deploy
these five apps to an environment, it
will it will try to deploy all five
apps, but it will find that the three
apps that you haven't modified is the
old version and is probably the one that
is already installed in the environment
and will therefore skip that and then
only deploy the two apps that you
actually modified.
I can see that we right now we are
selecting a full build whenever you make
any changes to settings. Um that is
probably a little bit too aggressive. So
um and update Elgo system files for
example will will cause a full build
afterwards uh which is probably too
much. So, we might make a change to
actually
only do a full build on config changes
or settings changes if some of these
settings changes
actually have any impact on the apps
generated. Um, I don't know if that's
possible, but it might be something that
we could look into. Right now, as soon
as you change any setting in any of the
settings files, it will trigger a full
rebuild. If you change settings in the
settings variables, it will actually
not. So, yeah, not ideal. Um, but else
the incremental build should work.
Um, if you just modify the app, it
should only build what's what's been
modified since the last known uh good
Alexander says, "In this scenario, I'm
running a dispatcher to start my CI/CD
for specific branches at different times
during the
week. How would that work with
incremental builds? So, if you set up
the builds on a schedule,
um you can specify that on schedule that
you'll run incremental builds on a
schedule as well. If you trigger the
builds with like a workflow run on um on
the CI/CD workflow, then it will not do
a incremental build. Um you kind of need
a way to to force a full build and we
decided that running the CI/CD workflow
manually would be triggering a full
build.
Um so but if you set up the CI/CD on a
schedule uh you can specify incremental
builds on schedule equals true and it
will do incremental builds on the
schedule as
well. Is there any way to make a build
fail if there are any warnings in the
code from code analyzers like code
cup?
Um, is that because they they do
warnings today
or is that how it is?
You can specify fail on if you want to
fail on warnings as well. And I can't
[Music]
remember if there's any any way
to specify
um that you treat these things as errors
instead of
warnings. I think there is a a way to do
that. I think further down in the
settings, if you scroll down, there's a
setting called treat warnings as errors.
I think it's a container helper setting
though, but I think it should be setable
from within algo. Yep, exactly. Yeah, a
list of algo which should be treated.
So, it's actually an array. Yeah, was
what I was looking for. Yeah. Um where
you can take those warnings and treat
them as errors. Uh but it'll be a a list
of AL warning codes that should be
treated then as errors. And yes, that is
a container helper thingy.
You can also set fail on to warning.
that'll fail your your workflow if you
have any warnings
[Music]
um in that sense.
says, "I would like a workflow where you
can simply specify a time and the CI/CD
process is scheduled to run at that
time.
Example, if a customer wants the
deployment at 8:00 p.m., the developer
should schedule it to uh during working
hours to automatically execute at 8:00
p.m. Is that something that could be
implemented? Um, yes, it can be
implemented. It's not something we can
do out of the box.
It almost feels like something that
GitHub should implement that run this
this workflow with these parameters at
that time, right?
Um I
did
see right now what you set up is is is a
chron tab and I guess that can be used
for a specific time.
[Music]
Um, I did add
a think I did that to GitHub issue at
some point in time. I I described how
you can create a workflow that'll
trigger a publish to an environment at a
specific time. like I had a a partner
who wanted to deploy to to the late the
the the latest released version to the
customer every Friday evening at 8:00
and and you can create a small YAML file
with some settings and and uh and and do
that. That'll run every Friday evening
and if you haven't released anything
over the last week, it will just do
nothing because that's the same version
that already was uh deployed. that
that's definitely possible, but but you
it sounds like you want to be able to
control it a little bit
uh further and that would be something
we had to yeah take as an as an idea if
you can again create a GitHub issue with
this one and and we can put into our
backlog and and see when we can uh
process that.
It should be possible to to do that
without huge interfering in algo for
GitHub. So if it's something that any
partner would like to take a stab on and
contribute with to ALGO, that would be
perfectly fine as well.
Is it possible now in the future to
trigger a test test minor or test major
up before deploying to environments like
prod?
Um it is not something we will chain
um automatically.
It's something I mean the deployment to
prod is is I guess something
um well what you can do actually just
came into my
mind you what you can do is you can you
can use the build modes but that would
like require you to every CI/CD build
you can you can build those uh in three
different modes one default one for next
major and one for next minor
And then your CI/CD will actually
um will actually like run
uh both all three builds uh and and and
will only succeed if all three builds uh
succeed there. So that's definitely
possible in that sense. But um it's not
anything we are going to yeah hook up to
the deploy to environment or anything
like that that you'd run these things
first. I think there was a chat message
here. I use CCD schedule 30 star 1245
um which is like at half past midnight
GMT Monday, Tuesday, Thursday and Friday
I guess. Or is it Tuesday,
Wednesday, Friday,
whatever.
Yeah, I think Maria's right. The
question is about a one-time schedule,
like being able to say, I want to run
this at a specific time later.
Any more
questions? Still have some
time.
Any questions for you guys in
Lub for Even
um so
says there's an AL warning.
think field length, but I have no
idea. Any of you in the view knows what
that one is or how they can fix that to
no longer be warning
and overcome
Please don't add things in the chat.
Please add them to the Q&A tab instead
so we don't have to switch back to the
chat to see these things. So add
questions to the Q&A tab instead.
[Music]
Um about
the question about the warning.
The
track about the question question
uh about the warning. Uh I think it's a
yeah sorry about the issue with the
audio in the room. Uh I think this is
something that should be ignored. But I
think this is not a very good example
how like changing length of fields is uh
done. Uh it's because it's generally
like it's a sequel change. So there has
to be like um another field that is has
the proper length and these fields
cannot exist um cannot coexist. So, it's
kind of like while the old field is
present, the new one isn't. And like
there's going to be like a version where
like the the new field will have like
the the proper the proper length. Um I I
I think the you could just maybe like um
add like some pragmas or something to
notice once. Uh it's not Yeah, again
it's not anything you can you can do
anything about. So uh and also maybe
raise like such issues on Yammer. I
think there's u the community there is
very active when it comes to like uh the
application code and someone there could
could be able to help you
out. So Tom is asking about code signing
um in the chat. I'll like take
that. Um I can't get the code sign
certificate URL to work and we need to
sign our apps for apps
validation. Uh there we are. Now it came
here as well. I use the code sign
certificate URL secret name code sign
certificate password.
So,
um, typically people will not be able to
get a certificate and a password
anymore, but I expect that you still
have a pfx file and a password uh with
the validity that still should work.
Um, if you create
a a a secret which I mean a URL that
points to your pfx file which then
should be in a secure URL somewhere and
a secret
uh let's say you you have a secret
called code sign certificate URL that
points to your secret then you should
set code sign certificate URL secret
name to code sign certificate URL. So it
knows that uh I actually don't know if
that's default.
Um I think if you just create the code
sign certificate URL secret then um it
will point to your certificate and the
code sign certificate password should be
your password. So those two secrets you
should have. You shouldn't actually have
to modify anything with a secret name.
um they point then it should use the old
mechanism to sign the apps. The new
mechanism to sign the apps is either
using trusted signing on Azure or using
um uh Azure key to
um to host your your your certificate
and use uh net sign to sign those and
that's built into a go for GitHub. I
think looking at this and looking at
scenarios there should be a code
sign code signing MD here code signing
in algo that specifies in 2023 you were
not able to get pfx files anymore.
Um and you can use a keyboard here or
you can
use does it specify anything about
trusted signing here? probably not.
Um then trusted signing will
be we have a special one for
that or we'll
find
trusted signing here
uh which is a setting that where you can
set up like
um yeah to set up Azure trusted signing
uh which which will automate automate
the process uh 100% %
um this is the documentation for trusted
signing I
think
signing. Um but the old mechanism should
still work. Um I'm unable to test that
because I do not have a certificate that
still works.
uh and we've switched all our signing to
to trusted signing instead. So um which
is something you need to do probably
within the next I don't know how many
days or years or months your certificate
is still valid but you wouldn't be able
to get a new PFX file with a password.
You need to change that to either key
volt and net signing or trusted signing
with that. But that should be fairly
straightforward. But the current
mechanism should work if you just create
the secrets uh correctly and and yeah
maybe you need to
also
specify that that the sequence needs to
be taken into account. I can obviously
test that or
see
that if I get a second to look into the
default value of those things. Code sign
certificate. Yes. So the secret names
are set by default to these values. So
as long as you create the secret
codesign certificate URL codes
certificate
password
then the old mechanism should still
work. Anyone?
Give people a minute or two and if no
more questions appear
we'll we'll just close the office hours.
We had many good questions. Do you guys
in Liby have any questions for the
partners?
Not that I can think of.
So let's see going
first going
second. Well, I think we can safely say
that
uh probably no more questions will
appear. So let's give
people 10 minute back of their time and
[Music]
um let's get uh yeah see you guys in a
month. Uh so I think there's maybe one
more or what I think job raised his
hand. Maybe it was
a that Thank
you. I raised my hand. I
didn't.
Okay. Okay. There was one more here
coming. Before we used the create
release action and it worked out of the
box. Now something has changed few weeks
ago and we have to run CI/CD workflow
one more time before it
works.
[Music]
Um I saw I think I saw an issue on
GitHub on that topic, but I don't know
if that's the issue that you're talking
about. Did you create an issue on this
on ALGO
yesterday? Didn't have time to look into
that one yet.
Um I don't know of of anything that
should
be changed or a lot of things changes
but not something that should cause that
behavior. So um
so Dominique if you could create an
issue if you don't haven't already done
that then we should take it there some
sounds like something with nuke it I
don't find I don't find the artifacts
the first time strange
um did you create an issue on on
github.com/microsoft go else I recommend
that you do that and then let's uh let's
figure out how to how to solve that.
Um that should not there should not be
anything there.
Yeah, thanks Tony.
I just wanted to ask something if
possible. um do you foxy um values in
using the discussions features on GitHub
where we can maybe post announcements or
where you can ask your Q&A and don't
have to like wait for the monthly office
hours right now as it is structured uh
people typically open issues even if if
the issue is not really an issue but
it's more of a question we've been
contemplating using the Q&A section in
the descript discussions but haven't
really done
anything. Um, if you could I I'm not
sure like how to
actually ask for your opinion here.
Maybe like
u maybe I can ask a question in the in
the Q&A and then you can uh give your
answer. No. Yeah.
And maybe we should remove the the
question template from the issues and
point to discussions instead.
Um, I know that I
have haven't been as active on answering
discussions as I have on issues that
might be a reason
for for people to using issues more than
discussions. But if
we if we are
more alert to
um discussions there might be
something that could help.
Um, good
ide. I think majority of people have
voted left and uh I don't
think there are any more questions. So
um yeah, let's look at the discussion
thing to see how we can make that work
for people and
[Music]
um and thanks for joining us.